Autoregressive and moving average models tend to capture different relationships.
自回归模型和移动平均模型发现的关系不一样
The nice thing is, you can get the best of both by adding them together.
好处是 可以将它们加到一起 同时利用这两种模型的优势
An autoregressive moving average is defined with a p and q.
自回归移动平均模型由 p 和 q 定义
The p is the lag for the autoregression,
p 表示自回归的滞后值
the q is the lag for moving average.
q 表示移动平均的滞后值
A variation of the autoregressive moving average
自回归移动平均模型的一个变体是
is the autoregressive integrated moving average.
自回归求积移动平均模型
This concept is used in a trading strategy called Pairs trading.
在交易策略中 这个概念叫做配对交易
First, let's build some intuition that will help us when
先介绍几个有助于我们学习
we study autoregressive integrated moving averages.
自回归求积移动平均模型的概念
Let's say we want to describe the position of a turtle.
假设我们想描述乌龟的位置
The turtle is walking at a regular pace.
乌龟在匀速行走
So, its position goes from zero,
它的位置从 0 变化到 1
then one, then two, and so on.
再到 2 等等
We noticed that the turtle is moving at a regular pace.
我们发现乌龟以匀速行走
So, we can describe its speed,
所以可以用一个数字
or the distance over time,
描述它的速度
as a single number.
或随时间推移的距离
For example, this turtle is moving at one meter per second.
例如 这只乌龟每秒移动一米
If we plot the turtle's position over time,
如果绘制乌龟随时间推移的位置
it is not constant.
会发现位置不是常量
Its position over time will look like a line that slopes upward.
看起来是一条朝上的线
However, if we plot the turtle's speed over time,
但是 如果绘制乌龟的速度
it is a constant one meter per second.
会发现它是常量 即 1 米/秒
The plot of speed over time is a horizontal line.
速度图形是一条水平线
Now let's think about how the turtle's position is related to its speed.
下面思考下乌龟的位置与速度之间的关系
If we look at the turtle's position over time,
如果查看乌龟随时间推移的位置
the slope of that line is its speed,
会发现这条线的斜率就是速度
or meters per second.
即米/秒
Going the other way,
反过来
we look at the plot of the turtle's speed over time and take the cumulative sum.
查看乌龟随时间推移的速度并求累积和
So, for instance, at each second,
例如 在每秒
we add one meter.
我们都加一米
So, we get one meter,
加一米
two meters, three meters, and so on.
两米 三米 等等
This is actually the area under the horizontal line,
这是水平线下方的面积
and is also the position of the turtle as time goes on.
也是乌龟的位置变化
So, what did we learn here?
学到了什么？
In general, taking the difference between each period
通常 计算两个时期的差异
is called the time difference or item wise difference.
称为时间差异或项目级差异
If you take the time difference of your data,
如果计算数据的时间差异
you may be able to describe your data more easily as a constant number.
也许能够用常数更轻松地描述数据
If you remember from calculus,
在微积分中
taking the derivative of a straight line gives the slope of that line.
计算直线的导数可以得出这条线的斜率
This slope gives us a way to describe the line with a constant.
这个斜率使我们能用常量描述直线
To go from speed back to position,
计算积分
we can take the integral.
可以从速度得到位置
This is finding the area under the curve or taking the cumulative sum.
即计算曲线下面积或求累积和
Taking the integral lets us translate from the speed back to position.
计算积分使我们能够从速度得到位置
We will now apply these concepts of time difference to learn
接下来我们将利用这些时间差异概念
about the autoregressive integrated moving average.
学习自回归求积移动平均模型
Recall that regression-based time series models require the data to be stationary.
基于回归的时序模型要求数据保持稳定
When data is not stationary, the mean, variants,
当数据不稳定时
or co-variants may change over time,
均值 方差或协方差可能会逐渐变化
and it's hard to use the past to predict the future.
这时候很难使用历史值预测未来
One way to get a stationary time series is by
获取稳定时序的一种方式是
taking the difference between points in the time series.
计算时序点之间的差异
The time difference may also be called the rate of change or the item wise difference.
时间差异还称为变化率或项目级差异
We call that the rate of change between periods,
时期之间的变化率
or the rate of return,
或收益率
can be calculated by taking the ratio of the current price divided by the previous price.
可以计算为当前价格除以之前的价格
When you express your data in terms of logs,
如果用对数表示数据
this ratio becomes a difference between
这个比例就变成
your current log price and the previous log price.
当前对数价格与之前的对数价格之间的差异
When working with financial data,
在处理金融数据时
we usually find that asset price time series have
我们通常发现资产价格时序
a property such that their time difference is stationary.
具有一个特性：时间差异保持稳定
In other words, we like working with returns and
换句话说 我们喜欢使用收益率 而不是价格
not prices because the time series are more stable.
因为时序更稳定
In math terms, we say that the original price data is integrated of order one.
用数学术语表示的话 原始价格数据是一阶积分
We also say that the log returns of this data is integrated of order zero.
对数收益率是零阶积分
So, when working the time series,
在处理时序数据时
you can check if it is stationary using
可以使用增强型迪基-福勒检验
a statistical test called the augmented Dickey Fuller test.
检查数据是否具有稳定性
If the augmented Dickey Fuller test gives a p-value that is 0.05 or less,
如果增强型迪基-福勒检验的 p 值等于或小于 0.05
then we can assume that the time series is stationary.
那么可以认为时序是稳定的
If the data is not stationary,
如果数据不稳定
we can take the time difference then run
我们可以计算时间差异
the augmented Dickey-Fuller test to see if the time difference is stationary.
然后运行增强型迪基-福勒检验 检查时间差异是否稳定
If it is stationary,
如果稳定
then we can say that this time difference is integrated of order zero.
那么时间差异是零阶积分
We can also say that the original time series is integrated of order one.
并且原始时序是一阶积分
You may need to take the time difference multiple times.
可能需要多次计算时间差异
Then, once you find a time difference that is stationary,
找到稳定的时间差异后
you refer to the original data as integrated of
将原始数据称为 d 阶积分
order d where d is the number of times that you had to take the time difference.
d 表示计算时间差异的次数
Also, once we have a stationary time series,
获得稳定的时序后
we can model it with an autoregressive moving average.
可以将其表示为自回归移动平均模型
Note that being familiar with the integrated order
注意 熟悉一阶积分
one and integrated ordered zero time series
和零阶积分时序
will help you as you learn about co-integration and pairs trading.
将有助于你学习协整和配对交易